If you're watching this video, I'm
assuming you know that your
regular health insurance policy does
n't cover maternity and newborns.
Maternity means delivery and
related expenses, and
newborn coverage means the
period from birth to 90 days, which
normal health insurance does
n't cover. Friends, I've
analyzed more than 20 health insurance policies
and selected the top five that
cover maternity and newborns.
In this video, we'll discuss these five insurance policies:
their maternity coverage,
their benefits, whether it's
inbuilt or a rider,
whether both husband and wife
must be on the plan, or whether only the mother
can take it.
What's the coverage for newborns? Is vaccination covered? And
ultimately, in the end, we'll discuss
their premiums and
which plan we should select, premium-wise.
Hello friends.  I am
Ashutosh, your personal finance coach.
Stay with this video till the end. Let's
start the video. Health insurance
works on probability. Suppose if
100 people have taken a health insurance policy, then there is a
probability that only two or four of them will make a health insurance
claim. That is why the insurance company
gives us a cover of up to Rs 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 50 lakh at a very low premium. But
friends, when it comes to maternity,
if any person is taking a maternity cover, then
definitely he will claim it. In such a situation,
this maternity cover does
not depend on probability.
That is why the premium of the insurances with maternity cover is
a bit high.
So does it really make any sense to pay such a
higher premium to get a maternity cover?
Many times, the premium of some plans is
so high that the delivery will take place in that amount. So, should
we pay such a
high premium to get a maternity cover?
Friends, there is another important aspect of maternity cover
which we often
ignore.  Let's cover the newborn baby.
In most plans, the newborn baby
cover is linked with the maternity cover. This
means that if the plan is
covering your delivery or maternity, then only will
your newborn baby be covered. Many times,
after delivery, many complications arise with the child.
In my own knowledge, there is a daily based client of his
acquaintance. One of his friend's wife
delivered a baby and their children were
delivered prematurely. These
twins were born prematurely and had to be
kept in the ICU for about three to four months, for which
they had to pay a cost of more than Rs 30 lakh. So
friends, whenever we are taking maternity cover, we should
not only look at the cost of delivery but also
see how much
cover we are getting for the newborn baby along with the maternity.
Different maternity plans have
different waiting periods.
In this video, I have selected only those plans
whose waiting period is nine months.  There are
many other
plans which have a waiting period of 3 years, 4 years and
even 6 years.
But friends, no one does such long
family planning,
hence I have excluded those plans.
In this video, we will discuss
only the maternity related features of those plans.
If you
want to know all the features of those plans, then I have
already made dedicated videos on them, the
links of which you will find in the description and on the i
button above. The plans we have
selected are ICICI
Lord Health Advantage, Star Assure, Star
One Care, Niva Bupa Health Premia and
Niva Bupa Aspire.
Maternity cover is available for age group 18 to 45 in ICICI Lord. There is no maximum age limit in
Star Age Women's Care, Niva Bupa Health
Premia and Niva Bupa Aspire.
Waiting periods for maternity are nine months in ICICI Lord Health
Advantage.
You can avail maternity cover only after nine months.  You can take
24 months cover in Star Azor. In Star Women Care, the sum
insured is 24 months for Rs. 5 and 10 lakh
and 12 months for Rs. 15 lakh and above sum insured.
n b Health premium is 24
months. n p Aspire has
different waiting period for different variants.
48 months in Gold Plus, 24
months in Diamond Plus, 9 months in Platinum and Titanium Plus.
In cover type III Lord, you can take this cover in individual as well as
family floater. This means the
mother can also take this cover alone, but there will
not be much difference in the premium of both. In Star Azor,
maternity cover is available only in family floater, in
which presence of both husband and wife
is compulsory. Star Women Care
is also available for individual women. n p
In Health Premium and Aspire, presence of both husband and
wife is compulsory for maternity cover.
Benefit Type: In ECSI Lombard Health
Advantage,
we get the maternity benefit as a rider and for that we have to pay
three years premium upfront.
In Star Agere Ones Care Niva Bappa Health Premia and Aspire, this
maternity benefit is inbuilt.
Maternity benefit
up
to ₹10 lakh will be available in ICICI Lombard Health Advantage. This means if you have a
policy of ₹10 lakh, then a
sum cover of up to ₹1 lakh will be available to you for maternity.
In Star Agere also, up to 10 per cent off sum is available
in Star Ones Care for 5 lakh sum cover: ₹
25000, up to ₹50000 for 10 lakh, 15 lakh and 20 lakh sum covers,
up to ₹75000 for 25 lakh and 50 lakh sum covers and
up to ₹1 lakh for 1 crore sum cover.  Charges of up to Rs. 1 lakh will be available for
nb health premium. For 5 lakh sum sheath Rs.
40000 For 7.5 lakh sum sheath Rs. 60000
10700 15 75000 20 80000 Charges
up to Rs. 1 lakh will be available for 1 lakh, 2 and 3 CR policy. For
3 lakh sum sheath Rs.
4000 For 5 lakh, 5000 7.5 lakh Rs. 10000 10
12000 151000 Charges up to Rs. 25000 will be available for 20 and 25 lakh Rs. 2000000 For 50 lakh
and 6 CR policy,
friends, you must be thinking
that these charges are very less,
delivery expenses range from Rs. 0000 to Rs. 1 lakh
in delivery, but
friends, one of the most special things about this plan is that it  The
maternity benefit will be carried forward
and can be carried forward up to 10 times, that
is,
if you are getting Rs 12,000 in a policy of Rs 10 lakh, it will be carried
forward for the next 10 years.
If you are young and are
planning for maternity in the future, then this plan can be a
good option. Secondly, in this plan,
we get another option in which by
taking an additional rider, we can pay up the
premium for 3 years and get the benefit of 3 years
together. Acumatica
uterofetal surgeries and assisted
reproduction treatment are included. Star
Women's Care also includes delivery expenses, pre
and post natal charges, uterofetal
surgeries, assisted reproduction treatment,
voluntary sterilization expenses and
miscarriage due to accident benefits.
Delivery expenses and lawful termination are
included in Niva Bupa Health Premium.
Antenatal charges, vaccination for expecting
mother, delivery, surrogacy, delivery by  Surrogate
mother, termination of pregnancy, treatment
for infertility, charges for legally
adopting a child and assisted
reproduction treatment are covered. Newborn
benefits are covered in ICICI Lord Health Advantage.
Twice the maternity benefit. Newborn
baby cover is available over and above
two maternity benefits in Star Age. Benefits ranging from Rs. 2 lakh
to Rs. 4 lakh are available depending
upon the sum. 25% off sum is available in Women's Care.
Newborn baby benefit up to Rs. 10,000
is available in Niva Bupa Health Premia and Aspire, which is a very
good benefit.
Vaccination for newborn baby is available in both these plans. 1 per sum off for
first year vaccination in Lord Health Advantage.
Maximum up to Rs.
10,000 per child is available.
Not covered in Star Age. 5 lakh
and 10 lakh sum is available in Women's Care. 2500 and 15 lakh sum is available in Niva Bupa Health Premia and Aspire.
And above charges of 3500 will be available for sum assured
First year vaccination is covered in Niva b health premium As per the
list,
no vaccination is covered in Niva b Aspire Let's
discuss the premium for which I have
taken the example of a 30 year old couple for 10 lakh
sum assured and for zone one Delhi and NCR,
in Aaaa Lord we have to
pay an upfront premium of 3 years and also a
maternity rider has to be taken separately
whose premium for 10 lakh sum is
17339 Usually the cost of delivery is around 1 lakh,
so in such a situation
paying a premium of 1.6 lakh to get coverage of 1 lakh delivery is
very expensive
and that is why this plan is very
recommendable in Star Azhar
22290 Star Mamas has
2841 n b health premium is
2493 n b Aspire
1756 See premium wise  So, we can consider
any plan except Lord Health Advantage.
If you
are comfortable with the premium, you can also consider ICICI Lord.
For a higher sum assured
policy of Rs 50 lakh and CR, friends,
Star Women's Care offers an option
where single mothers can also plan on their own.
If you feel that
you already have a policy and want to
buy a policy only for maternity, you
can consider Star Women's Care.
If you want a plan with a two-year waiting period,
then you can select both Star Age and Health
Premium. The
premium for Health Premium is slightly higher,
but the new baby cover in it is
up to the sum assured. You
can also consider NB Spar if
you are planning for maternity in the long term
because its benefits will be carried
forward. Additionally, you
also get a Future Ready option in this plan
if you are single and purchasing this plan.  So,
if you take the Future Ready Rider,
your spouse will
not have to serve any waiting period with you.
I often receive inquiries about maternity. If a
complication is
detected during pregnancy, people want to take maternity cover only to
cover the newborn baby. However, let me tell you
that newborn cover is
a part of the maternity cover itself.
If an insurance is covering your maternity, that is,
delivery expenses, only then will it provide
you cover for the newborn baby.
If that insurance is
not covering your maternity, then it will
not cover the newborn baby either.
Friends, if you have any doubts related to maternity or
any health insurance related to these plans, then
you
can ask by commenting below. Friends, if you want to purchase a suitable health insurance plan according to your
current financial and medical situation, then
you
can also purchase it from us, in which we will help you in taking care of your current situation.  After
analyzing the situation, we
will recommend the right product to you and you
also get the benefit of lifetime claim support
with us. Friends, if you liked this video then
definitely like it and subscribe to the channel. That's all
in today's video. See you
in the next video. Thank you.